Kratika Raghuvanshi

K63 G, Top Floor, Sheikh Sarai Phase 2 , New Delhi, India

Kratika18@gmail.com Mobile: +91 8826473939

OBJECTIVE

Looking for a challenging role in a reputable organization to utilize my technical and management skills for the growth of the organization as well as to enhance my knowledge about new and emerging trends in the IT sector.

CAREER SUMMARY

Dynamic and motivated professional with nearly 6+ years' experience in generating and building relationships, managing projects, designing educational strategies, and coaching individuals to success. Adaptable and transformational individual with an ability to work independently, creating effective presentations, and developing opportunities that further establish organizational goals.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Kunskapsskolan Eduventures Pvt. Ltd, Gurgaon

<u>Technical Coordinator & Developer - Portal Development</u>

Jan 2014 - present

Notables:

- Responsible for leading, directing and managing all project operations to ensure consistently high levels of service, profitability and compliance.
- Overall responsibility for short/medium term planning and organisation of all resources.
- Handling different international projects simultaneously (Indian portals, Cambridge Portal, Saudi Portal, UK Portal, Swedish Portal.).
- Planning and designing of the portals and proactively monitoring its progress, resolving issues and initiating appropriate corrective action.
- Ensuring effective quality assurance and the overall integrity of the portal programme.
- Planning and executing multiple tasks to ensure controlled documents were managed per procedures.
- Attending regular progress meetings with Senior Managers and Directors.
- Participating in the recruitment and staff selection process.
- Actively mentor and supervise new employees during on the job training period.
- Ensuring that all processes are fully adhered to and all content changes are implemented as per requirements, to required timescales.
- Promoted to assume additional responsibilities as Technical Advisor providing expert guidance to the team.

- Ensuring that communication between departments is ongoing and utilised to maintain an environment of continuous improvement
- Developed, coordinated, and maintained process mapping activities and documentation.
- Coordinated cross-functional process development and identified opportunities and improve process.

Info edge India Ltd (Naukri.com), Noida, UP

IT Coordinator

April 2013-Jan 2014

Notables:

- Achieved highest levels of productivity, handling over 1,000 requests per week and averaging 200+ requests daily.
- Handling a team of 22 members.
- Earned good reputation for resolving complex issues and providing exceptional customer service.
- Assisted users with policies and procedures.
- Wide knowledge of Service Level Agreements.
- Escalated issues as needed and maintained communication with customer and Technical teams. Extensively utilized Remedy to record and track issues.
- Presenting written reports and analyses to senior managers.
- Worked on ticketing and inventory tools (OTRS, PC Visor) to accomplish the tasks as per the SLAs.
- Coordinate & Manage vendor management.
- Develop the company's inventory management strategy with the aim of controlling costs within budgetary limits, generating savings, rationalising inventory and maximizing available working capital.
- Manage and maintain the company's material and stocked product inventory including stock profiles and stock locations.
- Using electronic inventory tracking to scan stock and reconcile inventory.
- Asset management and software management
- Responsible for maintaining track records and MIS Reports.
- Maintaining effective business relationships with customers.

HCL Info Systems Ltd, Noida, UP

Technical Coordinator Jan 2012-Mar 2013

Notables:

- Handling a team of 16 members.
- Responsible for daily operations, including opening and closing the customer issues and tickets.
- Responsible for handling daily registered ticket countdown and maintaining MIS reports.
- Facilitate workflow, re-allocate resources, decrease call cycle time and ensure attainment of development goals.
- Create positive customer interactions over the phone consistently.
- Analyze and resolve complex data related problems.

- Actively mentored and supervised new employees during on the job training period
- Identify and escalate network and system issues to the appropriate group using ticketing system
- Communicated regularly with senior management and both technical and non-technical personnel to build effective cross-functional teams and ensure accuracy, consistency, problem solving and on-time project completion.

SKILLS

Business Skills:

- Driven and determined
- Strong ability to work with teams and multi-task projects under strict deadlines
- Responding positively and promptly to requests
- Managing change to meet business requirements
- Maintaining & developing good employee relations
- Excellent leadership qualities
- Innovatively solve problems with focus on producing significant bottom line results
- Excellent problem solving, analytical and time management skills
- Abilities in handling multiple priorities, with a bias for action and a genuine interest in personal and professional development.

Technical Skills:

- Working Knowledge of Photoshop, Dreamweaver.
- Working Knowledge of MS tools (Excel, Word, Office, Power point, etc).
- Working Knowledge of web technologies like HTML, CSS, Java script, Word Press, Sitevision Tools.

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

- Completed 12th from DAV Public School (CBSE Board), Kotdwara in 2007.
- Completed 10th from DAV Public School (CBSE Board), Kotdwara in 2005.

PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATION

- Completed MBA in HR from IGNOU UNIVERSITY.
- Completed B. Tech (Information Technology) from Institute of Science and Technology, Kurukshetra University in 2011.

OTHER ACHIEVEMENTS

 Participated in Global Technical Conference in Sweden by KUNSKAPSSKOLAN EDUVENTURES, Sweden in Aug 2016.

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Place: New Delhi

•	Name	:	Kratika Raghuvanshi
•	Permanent Address	:	B.E.L Road, Vill- Ratanpur Sukhroa, Kotdwara,
			Dist-Pauri Garhwal, Uttarakhand
•	Date of Birth	:	18 th November1990
•	Marital status	:	Single
•	Language known	:	English, Hindi
DECLARATION			
I do here by declare that all the information furnished above is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.			
Date:			

(Kratika Raghuvanshi)